Noushad Puthen Peedikayil

Staff Software Engineer

 ♥ Berlin, Germany · ☑ to.noushadpp@gmail.com · ┗ (+49)-17634-383907 · ♥ noushad-pp · ≧ noushad

OBJECTIVE

Experienced full stack developer with an eye for big picture and strategic execution. Broad industry experience including extensive exposure to startup and corporate environments alike. 9+ years of professional expertise with strong leadership & relationship-building skills. Recently got curious about Domain Driven Development, functional programming, event-driven and distributed systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Linked in

FlixMobility Tech GmBH

Berlin, Germany Nov 2023-present

Staff Software Engineer

- Design and implement scalable software solutions to optimize complex revenue management processes.
- Analyze complex business requirements and translated them into technical specifications and delivering them.
- Working together with domain technology office and domain product officer to define the domain roadmaps.
- Collobarating with multiple cross functional teams including product, design, leadership and business stakeholders.
- Helping the domain growth and evolution in terms of staffing, technology, and processes. For eg: Saw through the transition from monolith to microservices, splitting the team into smaller domain focused teams, etc.
- Ensuring the delivery of the stakeholder expectations via SLOs.
- Provided technical leadership and mentorship to junior engineers, fostering a culture of continuous growth & innovation.

Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2019-Oct 2023

- Architect and maintain microservices for real-time revenue data analysis, ensuring high availability and reliability, for data-intensive real time applications.
- Making decisions autonomously to deliver solutions that meet stakeholder expectations based on the user research and feedback information.
- Error discovery, monitoring and metrics collection for the services.
- Create and maintain automation pipelines, testing frameworks and deployment strategies.
- Technologies: Typescript, NodeJs, NestJs, React, MySQL, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Datadoq

Pole Tech Labs Pvt Ltd

Ahmedabad, India Apr 2017–Sep 2018

Frontend Architect

- Led the frontend team in designing and developing a scalable, modular, and maintainable architecture for a B2B2C SaaS product.
- Creating high-level product specifications & design documents and converting them into architectural blueprints for development team to follow.
- Collaborating with various stakeholders to determine software requirements.
- Responsible for designing, reviewing, debugging & deployment of source code.

Founding Full-stack Engineer

Jul 2016-Mar 2017

- Joined as full stack developer in core engineering team which designed & implemented a social network of location-based marketplaces & has users from 15+ countries.
- Architected & implemented admin-business dashboards using angularjs framework from scratch.
- Created web version of product from scratch self learning React-Redux libraries.
- Implemented backend features required for product using NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDb, Redis
- Ensured consistency of data across platform using cron jobs & saved significant amount of Devops time with automation scripts for deployment processes.

Bullfinch Softwares
Software Engineer
Bangalore, India
Jul 2015-Jun 2016

- Worked in various projects as full stack dev with Ruby On Rails, angularis, HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript, PHP, WinJS.

- Ported vanilla js projects to angular based projects.
- Created and optimised responsive web applications for e-commerce platforms, restaurant, insurance, survey, education sector clients.
- Created & worked on Windows mobile application using WinJS framework for enterprise-level client.
- Worked closely with clients to understand requirements.

Toobayna Holidays

Co-founder

Sulthan Bathery, India Aug 2013-Jun 2015

- Started the entrepreneurial journey with a company that undertook event management & travel-tourism services.
- Supervised company properties, served as guest relations manager.
- Overviewed company's social media presence and email communications.

SKILLS

- Languages/Tech: Typescript, MySQL, MongoDb/DynamoDb
- Frameworks: NodeJs(NestJs), ExpressJs, React, Angular, styled components, css modules, BEM, REST, GraphQL
- Libraries: effect, fp-ts, Redux, SWR, socket.io, Recharts
- Tools: Git, webpack, parcel, rollup, pnpm, yarn, npm, Webstorm, Datadog, rollbar
- Cloud: AWS, Azure-AD, Oath0, Heroku, Netlify, cloudinary, Firebase
- Testing: TDD, unit testing, cypress, jest, enzyme/testing-library, supertest, BrowserStack
- Automation: Kubernetes, Docker, terraform, gitlab-ci, github-actions

EDUCATION

University of Kannur

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering

Govt Eng College, Wayanad 2010–2014

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Winner XBUILD18 The official unmanned systems' hackathon of AUVSI https://xbuild18.devpost.com
- $-\,$ Participated in Blackberry 1k developer program 2013
- College cricket team captain